[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
[gagging]
ELI: He didn't come through!
KLEINER: Where is he?!
ELI: Behind you.
KLEINER!
[Kleiner screams]
ELI: Shut it down! Shut it down!
SHUT IT DOWN!
KLEINER: Gordon, you must
get out of here! Run!
I CAN'T MOVE!
KLEINER, WHY?! WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?!
OH! Oh!
Oh God, paparazzi.
No!
NO PHOTOS!
I'M A VICTIM!
I DON'T WANT THIS IN THE NEWS!
THIS IS BETWEEN ME AND KLEINER!
WE HAVE A LOT TO DISCUSS!
YOU'RE NOT A PART OF IT!
Are they following me?
Oh, God! I'm still shaking!
I'm still not convinced
that the field is fully off
and I won't just get ripped away any second.
So what now? I guess I should get breakfast?
BARNEY: Hey, Gordon!
DAH!
I'M DONE! NOT AGAIN!
BARNEY: The Citadel's on full alert--I've
never seen it lit up like that!
What?
BARNEY: Get out of City 17
as fast as you can, Gordon.
BARNEY: Take the old canals, right?
I don't know where anything is.
BARNEY: It's a dangerous route,
BARNEY: but there's a whole network of
refugees and they'll help you if they can.
BARNEY: I'd come with you, but
I gotta look after Dr. Kleiner.
He can look after himself!
BARNEY: Before I forget, I think
you dropped this back in Black Mesa.
What?
BARNEY: Good luck out there, buddy.
Hey!
BARNEY: You're gonna need it.
No, hey! Stop goofing around! I
need a gun! I know you have one!
And some cash!
Are you going to make me come up there?
This is such a clown show.
Well, I guess I believe him when he
says I should get out of the city.
Why did he hand me a crowbar? That's weird.
How about a map or a phone number?
[grunting]
GUESS I'LL USE IT SINCE I HAVE IT!
I could've climbed this.
Dammit, you know what the
problem is? I just got Kleinered.
I have a hundred questions I
need answered, I need supplies,
but instead he distracted me, got
me excited about his experiment,
then almost got me killed--again--
and now the experiment's
done, I'm out the door.
Dammit, Kleiner!
Oh--OH!
NO! NOT AGAIN!
HAH!
[muttering]
BLAH!
FUCK YOU!
Okay, I guess that IS a
good use for the crowbar.
Like a giant robot mosquito.
See, I'm adapting.
[gunshots]
HOLY SHIT!
This is bad, bad, BAD!
That is the one advantage
I had and now it's gone!
DAH!
[grunting]
What do I do? What do I do?!
Uh!
I'll run! Yeah, they'll never think of that!
[train whistle]
Huh?
Oh, God, God, GOD!
WHY ARE THERE SO MANY COPS IN A RAILYARD?!
This has gotta be a fascist state.
How does that go? Mussolini
made the trains run on time?
AH! NO! HOW DO YOU HAVE A LINE OF SIGHT?!
Oof!
JESUS!
Do they get a bonus if they hit me?!
Are they climbing the fence?
Good. They're lazy.
Yeah, I guess the trains WOULD run on time
if you have 20 fucking cops
waiting to blow your head off!
Maybe they think I'm a conductor.
[yelling]
Oh! Sweet concrete! I never
thought I'd miss you so!
Okay! Time for our morning jog!
WOMAN: Please! Stop!
Nope!
This is a problem!
I guess my only play is
to be cool and walk by.
"Hi, officer. I'm just a goon in
body armor holding a fucking crowbar.
"Nothing suspicious here."
AH!
STOP THAT!
OKAY, YOU'RE PLAYING FAIR! EN GARDE!
GUN! YES!
WOMAN: They're going to
be looking for you, now.
WOMAN: You'd better run. There's
nothing else you can do here.
THEY'RE ALREADY LOOKING FOR ME!
WHAT THE HELL DO YOU THINK
I'M DOING, TRYING TO RUN?!
No, I just woke up today
and decided to bash some cops'
heads in for no reason, y'know?
Oh no.
DROP IT!
FINE! DO IT THE HARD WAY!
Crossing lines here... Gunning down cops.
Now I'm no better than what's-her-face.
And she's the reason they're after me!
I swear to--
[gunshot]
AH!
Yeah! Why not?! I'm in this deep;
might as well keep shooting.
See, that's the--
[chopper]
Ah!
Oh wait. Pigeons aren't cops.
That's just a comic book, or... something...
Okay, things look kind of quiet.
Maybe I'm finally a step ahead now.
Though that railyard
looked pretty quiet, too.
God, they were right on top of me!
Did that Barney guy tip them off?
Wait, am I just a decoy?
[train whistle]
Yeah, I see you.
Why did Kleiner make me wear this suit if
he sent what's-her-face in just her clothes?
I still don't have a helmet so it
wouldn't have saved me from an overload.
Are they just using me as a
diversion to draw fire off them?
Ah, I've gotta get out of here, though.
The cops are not THAT far behind.
As soon as they figure out how to
climb a fence, I've got problems.
Eh, this train's going too fast.
Maybe...
Oh, it's slowing down!
Maybe I could freight hop.
Shit, it's stopping.
That was quick.
Oh, you know what? We're
going to make this work.
Yeah!
Playing Frogger will save your life!
Especially if you're...
...a cop-killer.
So, I still need to--
[gunshots]
OH, THEY'RE HERE!
JEEZ! THAT WAS CLOSE TO MY HEAD!
WHAT THE HELL YOU DOING?!
Oh, that is bad! BAD BAD BAD!
YEAH! SHOOT UP A FLARE
SHOWING EVERYONE WHERE I AM
JUST IN CASE RADIO'S NOT ENOUGH!
Oh my God! It's a box of bullets!
The gods are watching!
But not you!
This society is so strange.
I can't imagine a box of bullets left at a
construction site and no one taking them.
They're the right caliber, too!
Yah!
Don't panic. Keep moving.
[gunshots]
Fuck...
These Charles Bronson motherfuckers
aren't giving up, are they?
Fine! I don't know what country this
is, but I can speak their language!
Complete sentences, too!
Yeah, they must've found a stepladder
or something to get over that fence.
[straining]
They really are some
trigger-happy fucks, though.
I never once heard a "freeze"
or anything in Russian.
[gunshots]
SPEAK OF THE DEVIL!
BLAH!
SPIES!
Stupid flare...
They saw me before I saw them!
Why is this stupid suit orange?!
It should've been urban camo.
WHAT WAS THE PLAN,
KLEINER?! WHAT WAS THE PLAN?
More bullets! Is this on purpose? Is
this some sort of predetermination?
[gunshot]
Ah!
They don't even wait to aim!
You just fire!
You see something moving, you fire!
Fucking cops...
There's too many... let's go!
Oh, a vent!
This is some sort of smuggling operation.
More bullets!
What the hell kind of vent is this?!
IT'S NOT VENTING ANYTHING!
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO LEAD ME TO SOME WAREHOUSE
WHERE I CAN SNEAK OUT THE OTHER
SIDE, NOT BACK INTO THE FIRE!
Fucking Christ! There's no end to them!
RAAAH!
Well, that's it! I'm fucked!
Are they retreating?
[gunshot]
No options!
Aaaah!
CAN'T YOU SEE I'M IN PAIN?!
WHAT THE FUCK?!
[siren wailing]
[siren wailing, explosion]
[siren wailing, bell ringing]
WAAAAAAAH! WAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
[bell ringing]
WHAT'S HAPPENING?!
Did they just pour burning oil on me?!
Is this is the Middle Ages?!
Is this a siege?!
Go away!
Do they think I'm trying
to siege the rail line?!
Is that why they're fighting to the death?!
They think I'm trying to
conquer their homelands?!
This is different than fighting soldiers.
[gunshot]
Ahh!
With soldiers, I was one enemy
among many. Here, I'm all they have.
I can't get a shot... Okay, run then?
That seems to be the answer to everything:
run and shoot people, and... run...
and... run...
Oh! Maintenance door!
Be open! Be open!
NO-HO-HO!
[chopper]
Oh! A helicopter!
That's... that's wonderful.
RAAAAAAAAAAH!
I'm not getting breakfast
this morning, am I?